Guide to the Carl Reeve Papers TAM.317
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Carl Reeve Papers
1910-2009
1970-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Reeve, Carl, 1900-1980
Reeve, Ann Barton
Steinmann, Susan Reeve
TAM.317
3.5 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 2 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box folder, and 1 oversize flat box.
Carl Reeve was a Communist, the chair of the Washington State CP, at one time served on the Central Committee of the CPUSA, was Educational Director of Party's Eastern Pennsylvania organization, and was in 1940 a Communist candiate for Senator from Pennsylvania. He wrote The Life and Times of Daniel De Leon (1972) and with his wife Ann Barton Reeve, James Connolly and the United States: The Road to the Irish Rebellion (1978). The Carl Reeve Papers contains research materials, notes and reviews pertaining to James Connolly and the United States, correspondence between Ann and Carl Reeve, manuscripts by Ann and Carl Reeve, a file on the Transport Workers Union of America, Local 100 (New York City), and a fragile copy of the Sinn Fein Rebellion Handbook: Easter, 1916. The collection also consists of essays, manuscripts, newspaper clippings, bibliographies and research materials related to Reeve's activities as a member of the communist movement. A significant portion of the collection includes correspondence with fellow comrades, supporters, in addition to a series of letters written to and from Ella Reeve Bloor (also known as Mother Bloor). The collection also contains personal writings, printed ephemera, travel itineraries, political songbooks, and photographs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Susan Reeve Steinmann in 2005. The accession number associated with this gift is 2005.020. An additional accretion of materials was donated by the Susan Reeve Steinmann in June 2018. The accession number associated with the accretion is 2018.101.
Biographical Note
Carl Reeve (1900-1980), a son, along with Harold Ware, of Ella Reeve Bloor (1862-1951) was a Communist, the chair of the Washington State CP, at one time served on the Central Committee of the CPUSA, was Educational Director of Party's Eastern Pennsylvania organization, and was in 1940 a Communist candiate for Senator from Pennsylvania. He wrote The Life and Times of Daniel De Leon (1972) and with his wife Ann Barton Reeve, James Connolly and the United States: The Road to the Irish Rebellion (1978).
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Scope and Contents
The Carl Reeve Papers contains research materials, notes and reviews pertaining to James Connolly and the United States; correspondence of Ann and Carl Reeve; manuscripts by Ann and Carl Reeve, including a review essay by the latter "Under Which Flag: A Play by James Connolly"; two small Irish nationalist posters, one memorializing Connolly (one in Irish); a file on the Transport Workers Union of America, Local 100 (New York City); and a copy of the Sinn Fein Rebellion Handbook: Easter, 1916, compiled and published by the Weekly Irish Times of Dublin, Ireland. A significant portion of the collection includes correspondence with fellow supporters, in addition to a series of letters written to and from Ella Reeve Bloor (also known as Mother Bloor). The collection also contains personal writings, printed events ephemera, travel itineraries, political songbooks, and photographs.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Appraisal
The repository's Curator made the decision to dispose of the wooden cover for a photograph album found in the 2018 accretion of this collection after a consultation with the Conservation staff found the object to be harmful to the rest of the material in the album. A photocopy of the cover was made and placed with the rest of the album.
Communists -- United States.; Women communists -- United States.; Ireland -- History -- Easter Rising, 1916; Ireland -- History -- 20th century.; Correspondence.; Photographs.; Connolly, James, 1868-1916; Transport Workers Union of America. Local 100; Steinmann, Susan Reeve; Bloor, Ella Reeve, 1862-1951
- Barton, Ann: "She Was a Gentle Woman" (Memoir about Her Mother), 1948-12-05 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Brewer, Karen: American Career of James Connolly (Masters Thesis), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Connolly, James: "Under Which Flag" Play, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Connolly, James: Poems (photocopies), undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Connolly, James: Research Materials, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Connolly, James: Memorial Poster, circa 1916 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- James Connolly and the United States Reviews, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Harju, W.A.: "The Finnish American: An Essay on Finnish American History", undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Notes regarding James Connolly, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Photograph of Gravesite, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Poblacht na hEireann: Poster, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Reeve, Carl: "Under Which Flag: A Play by James Connolly" Review, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Transport Workers Local 100, 1970-2009 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Writings: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Sinn Fein Rebellion Handbook: Easter 1916 (Compiled by the Irish Times) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, Publications, Pamphlets, Photographs, Manuscripts, and Printed Ephemera, 1912-2005 (Box 2, Folder 1-22, Box 3, Folder 1-6, Box Shared Tamiment C001)
- Wood Photograph Album Cover and Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 1-5)